<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Anas Nakawa</title>
    <link href="http://anasnakawa.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://anasnakawa.com"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T18:53:15.741Z</updated>
    <id>http://anasnakawa.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Anas Nakawa</name>
        <email>anas.nakawa@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    
        <entry>
            <title>Blogging with Docpad</title>
            <link href="http://anasnakawa.com//posts/blogging-with-docpad"/>
            <updated>2013-03-02T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
            <id>http://anasnakawa.com//posts/blogging-with-docpad</id>
            <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;it has been a while since my last blog post, which happened over 2 years ago..  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;usually i am not that active blogger, maybe because I wasn&amp;#39;t feeling comfortable with the blog engines out there, also lets not forget that most of the times i am a lazy person, especially when it comes to writing posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I hated blog engines ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;actually I think blog engines ( such as Wordpress, tumblr ..etc ) are great for writing posts for most people, but when it comes to a developer like me sometimes I just don&amp;#39;t feel that I have the freedom that I want..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;either if I want to share a code snippet with some fancy syntax highlighting, or if I want to provide some live demo, both ways I will end up looking for some plugin to satisfy my needs ... not exactly what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the answer should be much simpler, all I need is to write HTML/CSS &amp;amp; JS code at my convenience, and that was not much to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A better alternative..&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I started to hear about somthing called &lt;strong&gt;static site generators&lt;/strong&gt;, I even started to see some great front-end developers shifting their blogs into one of these generators..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first I was surprised that most static site generator implementations out there were built on ruby ( e.g: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/imathis/octopress&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; ), but since I am a javascript guy, I was looking for something more familiar to me...a Node Js implementation, and found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bevry/docpad&quot;&gt;Docpad&lt;/a&gt; was exactly what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;getting started with docpad was straight forward, they have some nice set of &lt;a href=&quot;http://docpad.org/docs/skeletons&quot;&gt;pre-built skeletons&lt;/a&gt;, so I cloned their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/docpad/twitter-bootstrap.docpad&quot;&gt;Bootstrap Skeleton&lt;/a&gt;, and got my hands on this nice technology..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is worth mentioning that this site was not only inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://premiumpixels.com/&quot;&gt;Orman&amp;#39;s Clark&lt;/a&gt; great designs, I actually transofmed his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumpixels.com/freebies/code-editor-app-psd/&quot;&gt;Code Editor App&lt;/a&gt; completly into what you see over here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Code Editor App - By Orman Clark&quot; title=&quot;Code Editor App - By Orman Clark&quot; src=&quot;http://turbo.premiumpixels.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/preview.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Site code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can find the source code of this site hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anasnakawa/anasnakawa.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, go a head make a fork, and have it at your own site, I will be more than happy :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        </entry>
    
</feed>